Noémie Tapie

User Experience Researcher & Designer

noemie.tapie@gmail.com noemietapie/projects linkedin/noemie-tapie

User Research Prototyping User Testing Redesign

Team player Creative thinking Communication

ABOUT ME

International student in Human-Computer Interaction, I follow my passion for user experience design around Europe. With analytical skills, creative thinking, a curious and open mind, and a sunny personality, I know how to motivate myself or a team to achieve greater results. With a special interest for for user experience research and design, I am aiming for a career, where I can develop my professional and personal skills, have a positive impact on the future and take over responsabilities to achieve tangible results.

WORK EXPERIENCE

THALES USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER INTERN

February 2024 - now

THALES - GREEN OPERATIONS

• UX and UI design of a collaborative application for flight dispatchers, aiming at optimizing the fuel costs of flights by 5 to 10%.

Lásh р

USER EXPERIENCE RESEARCHER INTERN

May - August 2023

LABORATOIRE INTERDISCIPLINAIRE DES SCIENCES DU NUMERIQUE

- Organisation of the workflow of a multi actor and collaborative publishing tool.
- Conducting user experience research (Interviews, breakdown analysis, persona, user groups, user journey map)
- Prototyping of the intial interactions and preparing workshops to test them.
- Redesigning the interactions on Protopie

Supervisor - Michel Beaudoin-Lafon

External contact - Nicolas Taffin

Note - Participation in illustrating examples for a novel design methods publication by Wendy Mackay

statista 🗹

PRESENTATION DESIGNER

2020 - 2022

STATISTA

- Design of statistics and powerpoint
- Communication with all members of the publication workflow
- Training of new team members
- Occasional design of posters and flyers for company events.

CUSTOMER SERVICE

2018 - 2020

LANGUAGES

French - native English - fluent (TOEFL) German - fluent (Test DAF)

SOFT SKILLS

- analytical
- problem solving
- self-organized
- structured
- motivated
- team player
- communicator
- · creative thinking,
- curious
- open minded

HARD SKILLS

- Protopie, Figma
- Miro, Notion, Trello, Office 365, Pitch
- Unity, Blender, Shapr3D
- Illustrator, Photoshop, Filmora, Powerpoint
- VSCode, GitHub
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, Python, Flutter
- Design Thinking
- User Research, Prototyping, User Testing, Redesing
- · Psychology, sociology

INTERESTS

- Dancing, visiting friends, travelling, playing games, hiking, singing, cooking,
- Ethical and philosophical concerns, environment, well-being, inclusivity

EDUCATION



M. Sc. HUMAN-COMPUTER INTERACTION AND DESIGN



EIT Digital double degree, 2022 - 2024 Aalto University, Finland Université Paris-Saclay, France



B. Sc. HUMAN-COMPUTER INTERACTION

Hamburg University, 2018 - 2022, Germany

PROGRAMS AND DISTINCTIONS



INTERNATIONAL ADVISOR

Athene Guild, Aalto, 2024, Finland



GROUP LEAD VOLUNTEER AREA

SLUSH, Start-up event, 2023, Finland



AI AND DIGITAL WELLBEING

EIT Digital Summer School, 2023, Lithuania



XR AND E-HEALTH

EUGLOH Summer School, 2023, Germany, first place



AirBus GameJam

Airbus hackahton, 2021, Germany



EuVsVirus

Pan-European Hackathon, 2020



EXPO 2020

Campus exhibition, Germany, 2020, third place